5 chapter six of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna suul chapter six Liberty I was quite happy in my new
place, and if there was one thing I missed it must not be thought I was discontented;
all who had to do with me were good and
I had a light airy stable and the best of food. What more could I want? Why,
liberty! For three years and a half of my life I had had all the liberty I could
wish for; but now, week after week, month after month, and no doubt year after year,
I must stand up in a stable night and day except when I am wanted, and then I
must be just as steady and quiet as any old horse who has worked 20 years. Straps
here and straps there, a bit in my mouth, and blinkers over my
eyes. Now I'm not complaining, for I know it must be so. I only mean to say that
for a young horse full of strength and spirits, who has been used to some large
field or plane where he can fling up his head and toss up his tail and gallop
away at full speed and then round and back again with a snort to his
companions— —I say it is hard never to have a bit more liberty to do as you
like. Sometimes, when I have had less exercise than usual, I have felt so full
of life and spring that when JN has taken me out to exercise I really could
not keep quiet; do what I would, it seemed
as if I must jump, or dance, or prance, and
many a good shake I know I must have given him, especially at the first; but he
was always good and patient study study my boy,” he would say;
“wait a bit, and we will have a good swim and soon get the tickle out of your
feet.” Then as soon as we were out of the
village, he would give me a few miles at a spanking trot, and then bring me back
as fresh as before, only clear of the fidgets, as he called
them. Spirited horses, when not enough exercised, are often called skittish, when
it is only play; and some grooms will punish them, but AR John did not; he knew
it was only high spirits. Still, he had his own ways of
making making me understand by the tone of his voice or the touch of the rain If
he was very serious and quite determined, I always knew it by his voice, and that
had more power with me than anything else, for I was very fond of
him. I ought to say that sometimes we had our liberty for a few hours; this used to
be on fine Sundays in the summertime The carriage never went out on Sundays,
because the church was not far off. It was a great treat to us to be turned out
into the home paddock or the old orchard; the grass was so cool and soft to our
feet, the air so sweet, and the freedom to do as we liked was so pleasant— —to gallop,
to lie down, and roll over on our backs, or to nibble the sweet
grass. Then it was a very good time for talking, as we stood together under the
shade of the large chestnut tree end of chapter six